<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-04T14:22:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Curtis Schrum</title><subtitle>Father, Web Developer, Writer, Fat Guy</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Journey - Day 133</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Three-months-later/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey - Day 133" /><published>2019-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Three-months-later</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Three-months-later/">&lt;p&gt;100 days have passed since my last entry. A lot has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went off Keto because my leg swelled up and broke out, I was pretty worried. It did not get better so I went back on Keto but some test revealed my gall bladder (as I feared) was getting worse and my ALT’s in my liver were really high. So I went back to a clean eating approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, while I still think carbohydrate consumption (sugar I am looking at you) is the cause of most illness in my life and obesity. I am actually having more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more energy, I am enjoying my life. I do not eat sugar unless it cannot be avoided (fruit for example). I will occasionally have a sauce that has a little sugar in it, but a little of something is better than my previous life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quit all soda even diet soda. No tea, I drink water. If I must have a flavor to my water I will use an electrolyte packet which has an artificial sweetener in it. These are terrible for me so I do them sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My diet consists of 6 days a week clean, 1 day a week I can eat what I want but I still try to stay at a reasonable caloric limit. I eat when I am hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, I am eating the same diet that Mark Wahlberg, Dwayne Johnson, Arnold Schwarzenegger, Jay Cutler and many others eat. I eat clean during the week by that I mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lean meats,
Complex Carbohydrates like rice, sweet potatoes, and vegetables.
I eat right now around 3000 kcalories a day. 
I now workout 6 days a week, and have a workout partner which has helped keep me accountable. 
When I started on clean eating I did take some numbers and I will post them for comparison below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 30th 2019 -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 391.6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height Inches: 75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neck Inches: 19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chest Inches: 55&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bicep Inches: 16&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forearm Inches: 15&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrist Inches: 8.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stomach Inches: 57&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hips Inches: 56&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thigh Inches: 33&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calf Inches: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 31st 2019 -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 375.6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height Inches: 75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neck Inches: 19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chest Inches: 53&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bicep Inches: 15.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forearm Inches: 13.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrist Inches: 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stomach Inches: 60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hips Inches: 53&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thigh Inches: 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calf Inches: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August 27 2019 -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 388 (it is not uncommon to gain weight after coming off Keto)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height Inches: 75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neck Inches: 19.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chest Inches: 53.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bicep Inches: 15.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forearm Inches: 13.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrist Inches: 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stomach Inches: 63&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hips Inches: 54.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thigh Inches: 32&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calf Inches: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I gained some pounds and inches back but I am still lower than I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not where I hoped to be I had hoped to be around 345-350 right now. Alas, that was not meant to be. However, things are looking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workout schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All workouts are 3x10 or 3 sets of 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday - Leg Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/seated-calf-raise&quot;&gt;Calf Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/leg-extensions&quot;&gt;Leg Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/seated-leg-curl&quot;&gt;Leg Curls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/leg-press&quot;&gt;Leg Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/plie-dumbbell-squat&quot;&gt;Sumo Squats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday - Back Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/wide-grip-lat-pulldown&quot;&gt;Wide-bar lateral pulldown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/seated-cable-rows&quot;&gt;Cable row&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/underhand-cable-pulldowns&quot;&gt;Machine underhanded pulldown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/close-grip-front-lat-pulldown&quot;&gt;Close grip pulldown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/one-arm-dumbbell-row&quot;&gt;Lawn mowers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/hyperextensions-back-extensions&quot;&gt;Hyperextensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday - Shoulder Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/machine-shoulder-military-press&quot;&gt;Shoulder press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/reverse-machine-flyes&quot;&gt;Reverse Machine Flyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/side-lateral-raise&quot;&gt;Dumbbell Lateral raises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/barbell-shoulder-press&quot;&gt;Barbell shoulder press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10-15 minutes of cardio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday - Arm/Abs Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/dumbbell-bicep-curl&quot;&gt;Dumbbell Bicep Curl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/cable-rope-overhead-triceps-extension&quot;&gt;Overhead tricep extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/hammer-curls&quot;&gt;Dumbbell hammer curl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/triceps-pushdown&quot;&gt;Tricep push down&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/ab-crunch-machine&quot;&gt;Machine Crunches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday - Leg Day 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/seated-calf-raise&quot;&gt;Calf Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/leg-extensions&quot;&gt;Leg Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/seated-leg-curl&quot;&gt;Leg Curls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/leg-press&quot;&gt;Leg Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/plie-dumbbell-squat&quot;&gt;Sumo Squats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday - Chest Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/barbell-bench-press-medium-grip&quot;&gt;Barbell Bench Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/incline-dumbbell-press&quot;&gt;Incline Dumbbell Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/dumbbell-bench-press&quot;&gt;Dumbbell Bench Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/incline-dumbbell-flyes&quot;&gt;Incline bench dumbbell flys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday - Off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No workout, food cheat day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly am I eating? I am glad you asked. I eat clean (mostly) I do eat some stuff that is not great like Sam’s choice aged bacon and cheddar burgers. They are a good protein source, they are grilled so MFP is not exactly right on the fat content most of that coooks off on the grill. I do not eat enough vegetables which I have a problem here, I like veggies but my girlfriend hates them. I bought some stir fry veggies for food prep this week and will be adding them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also doing regular food prep (thank you Walmart Grocery orders).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all a much healthier lifestyle and I think a maintainable one. The workouts are medium intensity until I get a few months under me then I can step it up to 4x12’s and swap out some movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know exactly what I eat? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/diary/CJSchrum&quot;&gt;My food journal is public&lt;/a&gt; if you visit and do not see food logged? Message me on MFP or IG and pester me to enter my food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">100 days have passed since my last entry. A lot has happened.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keto Journey - Day 33</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Day-Thirty-Three/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keto Journey - Day 33" /><published>2019-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Day-Thirty-Three</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Day-Thirty-Three/">&lt;p&gt;A month has passed. I did my 1 month weigh in today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a weird quirk in the data but it is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 30th 2019 -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 391.6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height Inches: 75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neck Inches: 19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chest Inches: 55&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bicep Inches: 16&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forearm Inches: 15&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrist Inches: 8.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stomach Inches: 57&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hips Inches: 56&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thigh Inches: 33&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calf Inches: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 31st 2019 -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weight: 375.6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Height Inches: 75&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neck Inches: 19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chest Inches: 53&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bicep Inches: 15.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forearm Inches: 13.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrist Inches: 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stomach Inches: 60&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hips Inches: 53&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thigh Inches: 30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calf Inches: 20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall great losses. Weird quirk in that my stomach gained 3 inches when I feel smaller but data is data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lost 16 pounds in May including traveling to Las Vegas for 4 days for work. I lost April 1 - April 30 on clean eating only 10 pounds. So 23% of the weight I have lost since April is due entirely to Keto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is more than that though, I do feel better. However, financially this has been very expensive. I have nearly doubled the food budget doing Keto. This seems inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still I like the new lifestyle, the cravings are pretty much gone. I do not go hungry which is nice. I have not walked into a Gym yet and am losing weight at a nice steady pace. My clothes are getting more loose which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of this has been helped by DietDoctor.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pair of jean shorts I could not wear in April fit me again which was a great confidence builder. Clothes I bought for my work trip are getting baggy which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly the back pain is virtually gone. I can walk to and from my car with no issues, walk around WalMart with no issues. Lethargy is still a problem some days as is brain fog so I have definitely not achieved some Zen state of mental clarity that is talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am pleased with Keto and the lifestyle. I am becoming a ketovangelist. I have not been blogging as much as I wanted to but I am just busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A month has passed. I did my 1 month weigh in today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keto Journey - Day 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Day-Three/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keto Journey - Day 3" /><published>2019-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Day-Three</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Day-Three/">&lt;p&gt;Well the first two days of Keto have passed and I am not feeling as crappy as I did. Monday was difficult I was lethargic all day. Tuesday was not as bad but I still just felt drained all day, with brain fog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today though I feel quite a bit better. A little tired of let’s call them, bathroom visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have lost a lot of water weight the last few days, like 10 pounds of water has come off of me. So I look less puffy, it feels good to see 10 pounds come off the scale but I know its not real fat loss just water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still I was able to walk to the office this morning without feeling like I was going to die on the walk so that was amazing. I can tell this will be a difficult lifestyle to stick to, I am still having to lean heavily on the self discipline I have to not step out of the bounds of rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everywhere I drive its 2 for 5 this or $1.49 nuggets that sound so tempting. It is hard to stick to the Keto diet in some ways because it is drastically inconvenient but I also feel like that is just an excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out my landlord is a dietician, he agreed with my thoughts on going Keto so that made me feel better. The more I research, the more I read &amp;amp; watch the more sense it makes. Am I under the spell of Gary Taubes and others? Possibly. Do I give a shit if I lose weight, feel better, and am there to walk my little girl down the aisle when she gets married in 20 years? No. I do not give two shits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am tired of the constant battle about diet. There is science to back up what I am doing. Better science that what Ansel Keyes had at least. Does the body builder, clean eating diet work? Damn right it does. I have done it. But, it does not work for me at least not right now. I need to lose two hundred or more pounds. To get to my goal weight of 180 I would have to lose 220 pounds that is what I weighed at 24. So take that into perspective I need to lose an entire large guy of weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part is I need to do this quickly. The Doctor has already told me my liver is in bad shape, pretty soon my pancreas will give out. I am nearly 35 and I have been essentially treating my body like it is an amusement park for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done yo-yo dieting the last fea years. I would lose 50-70 pounds ger comfortable and then slide off the wagon. This blog is supposed to help with that. The letters to myself to remind me why I hate myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that sounds harsh but its time for truth. I am tired of pretending that I am okay. I’m not. Behind the confident bravado I have is a guy who literally hates himself. I talk about discipline but look at me. I cannot even stick to diet rules longer than three months. I have barely stuck to anything I have ever said I would do my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been fat most of my life. I remember having “man-boobs” when I was like 7. There was a time like at 14 I was in decent shape, then again in my late teens early twenties. When I left my first wife I got into pretty good shape, sadly thats because I was dating 18 year old girls at 23 and 24 years old so I kind of had to shape up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then somewhere around 2010-2012 working from home I started to gain weight. By 2014 I weighed 350. From 2014 to now I have yo-yo’d from a peak low of 300 to my peak high in April of 401 pounds. Long gone are the 2XL shirt days of 2008, long gone are the 42 inch pants. When I got down to 300 one of the joys I had was going to Wal-Mart and buying jeans off the rack. I cried in the changing room when they buttoned. Then … I just slowly fell apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My marriage started to tank. I took on a lot more stress. And, as usual stress is my eating green light. Pretty soon I was back up to 350, 360, 370. Then I tried the Gym and clean eating. I got down to 330 … then fell off the wagon. Then I shot up to 380 in April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I seem to go through these cycles where around April I start feeling like I need to lose weight and it lasts a few months then it goes away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 2017 I started Keto the first time, by the time I left my second wife I was down to like 330 in June. I could wear 3X’s in fact I still own shirts I bought myself on my 33rd birthday that are 3XL polo’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then well … I just kind of took on one of the most stressful periods of my life over the last two years. Though I have tried to control it and diet during that time. Here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I weighed 385 pounds down from 401 April 1. I weighed 395 Sunday, I weighed 391 yesterday morning. I know its water weight but dammit its nice to feel like I can walk to the office without thinking I am going to die. If I cannot do it this time … Im not sure I will make it to Christmas this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark cloud of depression is starting to really brew over me, this journey is one of the few things that has pushed it back and make see sunshine again. No one knows it but me … but there was a time after my surgery where I didn’t care if I woke up the next day. I was not suicidal I just didn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Well the first two days of Keto have passed and I am not feeling as crappy as I did. Monday was difficult I was lethargic all day. Tuesday was not as bad but I still just felt drained all day, with brain fog.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some things change, and some things do not</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/The-First-Entry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some things change, and some things do not" /><published>2019-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-First-Entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The-First-Entry/">&lt;p&gt;A new journey must begin. Last summer I set out on a journey for weight loss it did not go well. It ended around the time I had my life overwhelmed by work, followed by surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many obese people like to make excuses for how the end up falling off the wagon, this is exactly what I did. I found excuses to fall off the wagon, and then my Appendix ruptured and due to complications during surgery I balooned to 400 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the heaviest I have ever been, and it is defeating. So I decided to start this blog for no one really but me. I want to record why I am losing weight as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also record what I am doing. This is no holds barred, I am even including images. At the start of April I weighed 401 pounds and I began the process of clean eating 6 days a week and 1 cheat day. I have not started working out yet like last time I wanted to drop some weight first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/progress/20190401-side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What I look like now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, thats me. That was on April 1 and I wish it was an April Fools Day joke. I am big I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly after speaking to a doctor I got devastating news. I do not have diabetes, I do not have overly high blood pressure, I do not have many issues except one. I have high liver enzymes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my surgery it was discovered I have lost between 30-50% of my liver function due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fatty_liver_disease&quot;&gt;Fatty Liver disease&lt;/a&gt; this really was a gut check for me. It took me months to recover from surgery all the while I was gaining weight due to depression eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never hidden the fact that I have a very unhealthy relationship with food. I eat to celebrate a good day or happy event and I eat to lament a bad day or sad event. My addiction is everywhere, I blame no one but myself for the state I am in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got three teeth pulled, my appendix ruptured in December and I am starting to feel like my body is breaking down. I can see the sun rising ahead of me and I am running to catch up. Pink Floyd really had something figured out with the song Time, as I age the song means more and more to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what shall I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keto-again&quot;&gt;Keto Again&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am no stranger to Keto. I was on Keto for 4 months in 2017 and lost about fifty pounds, then my marriage collapsed due to a lot of reasons. I have dabbled with it since then but never been able to get going. The doctor wants me to lose 100 pounds or as close to it as I can get in 6 months which sounds very unhealthy. However, he is weighing it against the liklihood of death or liver failure. He prescribed Ketogenics more or less to get me there at least in the short term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to a dietitian she said Keto was a bad idea as it is not sustainable. So I did it her way for a month, clean eating. Steped up my activity levels. I will have lost 6-8 pounds in the month come months end. Which is right on her target. The problem is in 6 months that is about 42 pounds which is pretty below what the doctor asked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am facing month 2, I am losing sleep at night thinking about my little girl growing up without a dad. It is time for insane, it is time to extreme. This is the time to do whatever I can because if I don’t I may not see a years progress. If Keto does not work I am looking at a gastric surgery which I do not want as the risk are too great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured out what I needed for motivation. Just some notes to myself … I will include them here in the blog. I plan on hiding nothing during this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;letter-to-me-04-23-2019&quot;&gt;Letter to me 04-23-2019&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Me,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its April 23rd your 395ish pounds. You just had three teeth pulled, setup your monitor and decided to do this blog. You might forget along the way why you are losing weight so I am here to remind you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can barely walk to work from the car, your heart rate gets to 122-130 on the short walk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot take the stairs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None of your clothes fit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You bought new jeans and essentially blew them out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot walk through the store without needing benches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your knees hurt if you stand too long&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have a flight next month and you are terrified of being too large to fly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t want your mom to bury her son and it worries you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t want your daughter or your son to grow up without you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You finally are getting to a point in life where stress is so much lower than it was&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those my friend are ten of the reasons you are forcing yourself to lose weight. Don’t let me down, I am counting on you to come through for me, I need to you stick with this. No matter how bad you want to quit, no matter how hard it is, how tired you are from the diet you do not want to be back here again. You are going to die. Let’s do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is time to wrap this up for tonight. I plan to update this regulary. Keto starts May 1st. If I am not updating it after May someone who reads this should ping me on Instagram, or another social platform and ask me why I am not doing so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A new journey must begin. Last summer I set out on a journey for weight loss it did not go well. It ended around the time I had my life overwhelmed by work, followed by surgery.</summary></entry></feed>